Washington, DC

jesseflorig@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Full stack developer – 18+ years of client, server, database, and API development deployed to cloud platforms **Proven leadership** – experience leading teams in an agile software lifecycle to deliver enterprise solutions **Active security clearance** – TS/SCI, reinvestigation completed June, 2017; CI completed September, 2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SPECIALIST LEADER, APPLIED AI

December 2021 to Present

Deloitte, Washington, DC

Technical lead managing platform engineering and software development for Trustworthy Al Pipeline MLOps platform

CYBER WARFARE OPERATOR

August 2017 to Present

Delaware Air National Guard, New Castle, DE

Red Team Lead for Tacet Venari training event at United States Air Forces Europe – Air Forces Africa

VICE PRESIDENT, SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

February 2017 to December 2021

Ephemerai, Washington, DC

· Served as member of the executive leadership team driving innovation and software development efforts

SENIOR SOFTWARE SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT

August 2015 to August 2021

Novetta, Fort Washington, MD & Arlington, VA

- Designed and developed next-gen Base Defense Operations platform for United States Air Force using Node, React, MobX-State-Tree, Chakra UI, PostgreSQL, Mapbox/MapLibre
- Developed big-data web application in support of Air Force Information System Security Office (ISSO) using Django, AngularJS, D3, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Leaflet, and AWS; Lead migration to ReactJS and GraphQL
- Developed facial detection and recognition rapid prototype for internal R&D project using Node, Meteor, D3, MongoDB,
 Python, and OpenCV

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER

November 2013 to August 2015

Global Risk Advisors, Washington, DC, New York, NY & San Francisco, CA

 Developed secure web portal for executive clients allowing remote access to intelligence briefs and sensitive documents using PHP, HTML, JavaScript, D3, CSS, and MySQL

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

November 2011 to November 2013

International Business Machines, Pentagon, Washington, DC & ISAF HQ, Kabul, Afghanistan

- Designed and developed Intelligence, Surveillance, and Reconnaissance (ISR) data mart, aggregating data from multiple DoD sources in support of Office of the Undersecretary of Defense for Intelligence (OUSDI)
- Rapidly developed and deployed web applications to collect survey data from U.S. Forces Afghanistan and briefed analytic findings to senior United States decision makers

SYSTEMS SOFTWARE ENGINEER

March 2004 to November 2011

United States Air Force, Tinker AFB, OK & White House Communications Agency, Washington, DC

Developed the first web based mission planning and tracking system for Presidential Airlift Group (PAG) ensuring
integrity of data and increased communication for all Presidential air travel missions using ASP .NET, C#, HTML,
JavaScript, CSS, and MySQL

EDUCATION & TRAINING

USAF Computer Systems Programming Course, USAF Cyber Warfare Operations Course SANS SEC542: Web App Penetration Testing and Ethical Hacking Certification, CompTIA Security+